CRYSTAL ELSEY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I have always been the sort of person who loves to jump in and orchestrate a solution to a problem, or figure out how to make something that works, work even better. Coming from prior experiences in nonprofit, sales, and account management, I love being in a field where I don't have to choose between strategic and creative thinking -- the possibilities for inventive problem-solving are endless!



(615) 812-3731



hello@crystalelsey.com



github.com/CrystalElseyNSS



in linkedin.com/in/crystalelsey

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Developer (Nashville, TN)

Intensive six-month full-time software development bootcamp with immersive, lab-based learning in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, C#, .NET, and SQL fundamentals

- Git and GitHub for version control
- Simulated work-based learning environment
- Full-time remote learning April-August
- Emphasis on team-based development
- Applied knowledge of interpreting existing code

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Nashville Software School Nashville, TN Graduation Date: August 2020

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY

James Madison University Harrisonburg, VA

PROJECTS

THE HUNT

Client-Side Capstone

Dashboard application where job seekers can organize job applications, interviews, and follow-up tasks

- Built with hook-based React JS
- Full CRUD functionality
- Utilized Sketchboard.io and dbdiagram for planning
- Implemented JSON server to store and return data
- Used CSS, ReactStrap, and Canva for component design

NUTSHELL

Group Project built in hooks-based React JS

Multi-user social application built 100% remotely by a team of four

- Played lead roll in project planning, SCRUM, and MVP integrity
- Implemented full CRUD functionality on the Events Section
- Used GitHub to manage version control and workflow
- Utilized mock user authentication and session storage

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IREVIVE HEALTH & WELLNESS

9/2017-10/2019

Mobile Services Acct Manager

Nashville, TN

Clinic focused on intravenous hydration therapy and weight loss

- Promoted to new position to streamline mobile bookings
- Increased volume and revenue by 35%
- Oversaw scheduling and patient processing
- Developed repeat business by establishing rapport with clients
- Established systems to increase front desk efficiency
- Compiled content for informational and promotional materials

CHECKBOX CONCIERGE

10/2016-12/2018

Owner & Executive Concierge

Nashville, TN

Personal assistance company serving multiple clients

- Provided services in meal prep, space organization, budget management, personal shopping, and misc. requests
- Developed network of affiliates to provide client discounts in exchange for exclusivity and mutual promotion
- Used inbound and outbound marketing to grow client base
- Hired a managed a staff of two

Featured in Nashville Lifestyles Magazine's July 2017 issue

GORDON ESTATE WINERY

1/2015-10/2016

National Sales Director

Pasco, WA (Remote)

- Increased sales by 10-30% across a 15-state territory
- Conducted market analysis for product viability
- Launched four new markets in 2016
- Negotiated with distributors to implement competitive pricing
- Presented at sales meetings, wine dinners, and workshops
- Redesigned retail-based marketing materials
- Created quarterly newsletter communicating updates, initiatives, and sales techniques to sales teams nationwide

ATHENS DISTRIBUTING

7/2013-12/2014

On-Premise Sales Representative

Nashville, TN

- Increased territory sales by 15-20% by expanding company's portfolio presence in restaurants and bars
- Built relationships with buyers and staff by providing support, training, and customer service
- Created marketing and promotional materials to improve product exposure and consumer demand